<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Jaigouk.Kim]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let the ideas flow. ]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/</link><image><url>https://jaigouk.com/favicon.png</url><title>Jaigouk.Kim</title><link>https://jaigouk.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 2.0</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:56:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaigouk.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Switching between git profiles]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Maintaining multiple profiles are pain in the ass. Sometimes, it's easy to switch and commit your codes and push. So, I have my own setup to prevent a situation like that.</p><p></p><script src="https://gist.github.com/jaigouk/75fbbeb37f15e860d248ab7a47c32330.js"></script>]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/switching-between-git-profiles/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c797c10ff3b1d0024d3c2af</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 18:52:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maintaining multiple profiles are pain in the ass. Sometimes, it's easy to switch and commit your codes and push. So, I have my own setup to prevent a situation like that.</p><p></p><script src="https://gist.github.com/jaigouk/75fbbeb37f15e860d248ab7a47c32330.js"></script>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serverless Edge Computing]]></title><description><![CDATA[no server. but network.]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/serverless-edge-computing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bfc855344476f0024ece2ba</guid><category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category><category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:11:03 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/apartment-architecture-contemporary-271722.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/apartment-architecture-contemporary-271722.jpg" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"><p>What happend after I attended kandddinsky conf in October? I found that I got too lazy. I bought Kindle and read DDD Distilled and other books. There were lots of crazy ideas going on in DAG based distributed ledger thingy. And I got interested in edge computing. Yeah, I remember I've read the article from HN about Webassembly, But I haven't gone to the end of the post. Today, I read it again. </p><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-27-at-00.25.14.png" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"><figcaption>source: https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/10/webassemblys-post-mvp-future/</figcaption></figure><p>Fastly launched <a href="https://www.fastlylabs.com/">https://www.fastlylabs.com/</a> recently and I was able to find code snippets that looks familiar to me from Tyler McMullen's talk about Fastly lab. Well, I guess I don't need AWS lambda for these any more.</p><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-27-at-00.38.16.png" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-27-at-00.41.30.png" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-27-at-00.43.46.png" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"><figcaption>source: <a href="https://vimeo.com/291584445">"Software Fault Isolation and Edge Computing"</a> Fastly CTO Tyler McMullen</figcaption></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-27-at-00.49.45.png" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"><figcaption>source: https://github.com/uTensor/uTensor</figcaption></figure><p>Also, there are cool open source projects out there like noise from Perlin.net.</p><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/perlin-net-noise-chat.gif" class="kg-image" alt="Serverless Edge Computing"><figcaption>source: https://github.com/perlin-network/noise</figcaption></figure><p>Well, this doesn't end here. Combined with a tool like intel's movidius neural compute stick which costs $70 and tinker boards, then you can have something poweful in your hand. As Perlin's dev team envisioned you can have quantum computing in your palm. Since those companies are doing it as of now. I think "A supercomputer in the palm of your hand." will happen very soon.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Map to the future]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>in 90's, mp3 came up. and then lots of mp3 players showed up in the market. but in the end. ipod killed them all. and it evolved to iphone and it changed the world. It's about connecting dots for meaningful result to customers. And yes, they won't describe the future</p>]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/map-to-future/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5bfb59b83425e50024b57742</guid><category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 12:28:26 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/background-boardwalk-clouds-808465.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/background-boardwalk-clouds-808465.jpg" alt="Map to the future"><p>in 90's, mp3 came up. and then lots of mp3 players showed up in the market. but in the end. ipod killed them all. and it evolved to iphone and it changed the world. It's about connecting dots for meaningful result to customers. And yes, they won't describe the future in detail. You need to live in the future by living on the edge without losing focus. And you need to see those dots and customer's pain clearly.</p><p><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90247240/exclusive-lisa-strausfeld-is-developing-an-entirely-new-kind-of-data-viz">https://www.fastcompany.com/90247240/exclusive-lisa-strausfeld-is-developing-an-entirely-new-kind-of-data-viz</a></p><blockquote>“We’ve seen this diagram for neural networks, social networks, organizational structures. I’ve found these diagrams almost unintelligible. They just convey connectivity and complexity.”</blockquote><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://images.fastcompany.net/image/upload/w_596,c_limit,q_auto:best,f_auto/wp-cms/uploads/2018/10/3-what-would-a-google-earth-for-knowledge-look-like.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Map to the future"><figcaption>[Image: courtesy Lisa Strausfeld]</figcaption></figure><p>The prototype aims to demystify networks by allowing you to explore them virtually. To use it, you put on a VR headset and enter a three-dimensional timeline that is minimal and neutral on purpose–a counterbalance to more cinematic or illustrative VR experiences. Historically important women’s lives, drawn from a women’s history project at the New School, are visualized along the X axis. Each woman’s life stretches through the decades, represented by a long series of rectangles that symbolize years. Faint lines drawn between the women signify connections–friendships, correspondences, influences through the years.</p><p></p><p>blue ocean strategy is another one to see the gap.</p><p><a href="https://medium.com/wardleymaps/on-being-lost-2ef5f05eb1ec">wardleymaps</a></p><p><a href="https://medium.com/wardleymaps/on-being-lost-2ef5f05eb1ec">https://medium.com/wardleymaps/on-being-lost-2ef5f05eb1ec</a></p><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-04-at-10.48.26.png" class="kg-image" alt="Map to the future"></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-04-at-10.51.19.png" class="kg-image" alt="Map to the future"></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-04-at-10.49.52.png" class="kg-image" alt="Map to the future"></figure><figure class="kg-image-card"><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/11/Screenshot-2018-11-04-at-10.49.07.png" class="kg-image" alt="Map to the future"></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing OpenFaaS to the company]]></title><description><![CDATA[personal experience about spreading openfaas at work]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/evangelizing-openfaas-at-work/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b928bcd89441d0024b4ecd0</guid><category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:55:26 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-07-at-16.55.47.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-07-at-16.55.47.png" alt="Introducing OpenFaaS to the company"><p>My motivations to use openfaas were,</p><ul><li>learning tool for new languages</li><li>getting used to kubernetes</li><li>learn serverless architecture with no cost for aws</li></ul><p>I gave a tech talk to other developers at work with a demo and some people asked me to form a workshop. So, I cloned <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/workshop/">openfaas workshop repo</a> and I got a permission from head of engineering to go through it 1 hour per week. In the beginning there were 17 devs. as time passes, people were not able to attend it because they were simply busy with their work. </p><script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="d98cffa833d3427c84701ff083f5fd06" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script><p>Some people followed the lab notes if they were not able to attend the workshop. we have following lab note structure.</p><pre><code>## Lab 5 - Create a Gitbot

[official openfaas lab5 note](https://github.com/openfaas/workshop/blob/master/lab5.md)


** feel free to update our notes.**

TOC

1. following the offical lab note
2. what we learned
3. ref
</code></pre>
<p>After 10th workshop session is done, i wanted to push this to the next phase. But there were concerns about openfaas from other devs. It's still young and people didn't want to use it for our production environment. But it is ok to use it for internal tools. Not used for production but the impact can be huge based on the problem I tackle. Luckily, head of frontend team was enthusiastic about using openfaas. Because i told him that i was able to write graphql functions that are connected to Neo4j. It needs to be polished but i was able to show the working query.  The guy had a real problem. It was about having lots of PRs that are hanging for a long time. The repository is a legacy codes. And people hate to dive into legacy codes. Well, as a "smart developer", you can find ways to avoid the situation. in the end, the legacy repository ended up with those PRs that are waiting people to review and QA. It's not about serverless architecture. it's about code ownership and having a solid CI/CD work process. I suggested him to form a plan to do that. git-ops can be a candidate if it's well crafted with QA steps.</p><p>There might something I can help. And then I remembered OpenFaaS community is using <a href="https://github.com/alexellis/derek">Derek</a> - a serverless 🤖 to manage PRs and issues. </p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ccoeut-Psuw" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>If we add more "pipe lines" that makes sense to the frontend team, then we can use it to improve our daily work process. Yes, I agree that it's more about people problem. but it will accelerate the plan. Now, I found a chance to use openfaas at work at last. Good thing about my situation is that our backend will be broken into services and we're going to use kafka as our message queue. And it's possible to launch openfaas function with kafka-connector. (<a href="https://docs.openfaas.com/reference/triggers/">you can trigger your functions via sns, rabbit mq and cloud events too</a>) </p><p>People will see it working and feel good about derek and automation for chores. If people start to add more features or functions then they might want to replicate the experience for production environment. we can do it with "stable" service like aws lambda in the beginning but it will cost money. then openfaas is a good option. isn't it?</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Message queues]]></title><description><![CDATA[Nats vs Kafka vs etc. comparing message queues]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/message-queues/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b8ab5ebbe3831002481ad40</guid><category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 22:25:29 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/09/abstract-arrows-blur-394377.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/09/abstract-arrows-blur-394377.jpg" alt="Message queues"><p>Message queues are the backbone of your services.</p>
<p>If you have gone through MVP and passed the monolithic situation, you are probably thinking about something has to be done. There are lots of problems on the table. Especially, your organization has grown more than 15 devs, then it's possible that they want to use python for ML, golang for infrastructure, elixir for graphql api endpoint, etc. There are various ways to make it happen. grpc can be 1 possibility. Or, you can use message ques. After booming of mobile apps and IOT, the server side should be scalable and maintainable. And it's true that you can't just stick with 1 programming language and treat it as a silver bullet. Docker was the answer to that chaos and kubernetes is the winning orchestration tool. still, you need to figure out how to break things down and put them in kubernetes. Openfaas is using Nats-streaming and there are <a href="https://docs.openfaas.com/reference/triggers/">multiple options(kafka, aws sns, CloudEvents, RabbitMQ)</a> to trigger your serverless functions.</p>
<p>While investigating message queue options out there, I found that <a href="https://www.confluent.io/blog/publishing-apache-kafka-new-york-times/">Kafka is used at NYT</a> and usually have more scores on HN.</p>
<script async class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="84923a1b878a4b34aec2ff4f923a7ef2" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script><p>I found that openfaas is a good example for using Nats Streaming. FAQ doc says it supports memory or data store for messages.</p>
<p><img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/09/Screen-Shot-2018-09-01-at-15.18.20.png" alt="Message queues"></p>
<p>And openfaas is using in memory store for messages. the following snippet is from openfaas' <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas/blob/master/docker-compose.yml#L76">docker-compose.yml</a> file. you can find kubernetes config from <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas-netes/blob/master/yaml/nats-dep.yml">here</a></p>
<pre><code class="language-yaml">nats:
    image: nats-streaming:0.6.0
    # Uncomment the following port mappings if you wish to expose the
    # NATS client and/or management ports
    # ports:
    #     - 4222:4222
    #     - 8222:8222
    command: &quot;--store memory --cluster_id faas-cluster&quot;
    networks:
        - functions
    deploy:
        resources:
            limits:
                memory: 125M
            reservations:
                memory: 50M
        placement:
            constraints:
                - 'node.platform.os == linux'
</code></pre>
<p>I wanted to &quot;replay&quot; messages if something goes wrong. and then I found this comment from this <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/nats-queue-worker/pull/17#issuecomment-377000157">PR in nats-queue-worker</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you use a NATS Streaming server with memory store, it is true that if the server is restarted, since no state is being restored, the previously &quot;connected&quot; clients will stop receiving messages. Publishers would fail too since the server would reject published messages for unknown client IDs.<br>
The streaming server and streaming clients communicate through some inboxes. When the Streaming server is restarted, since it lost that knowledge, it can't communicate with existing clients. Moreover, even internal subjects used to communicate between the server and its clients contain a unique id that won't be the same after the restart).</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: If the NATS Streaming server connects to a non-embedded NATS Server, then if the NATS Server itself is restarted, that is fine, the client library's use of the underlying NATS connection will reconnect and everything would work fine (some timeout may occur for the operations that were inflight when the NATS server was restarted). This is because the Streaming server would still be running and its state maintained, so the communication can continue.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, I am curious if I change openfaas' nats-streaming config with PV like <a href="https://github.com/canhnt/k8s-nats-streaming/blob/master/charts/nats-streaming-ft/templates/pv.yaml">this</a>, then will openfaas fetch the previous messages even though the streaming server is down or nats-queue-worker is restarted? I will play with it and write the following up article.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do you need a free kubernetes env for playing with openfaas? ]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/openfaas-on-free-kubernetes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7fd4c10a40eb002461a284</guid><category><![CDATA[devops]]></category><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/cost-lite-cluster-month.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="openfaasonkubernetescheapestoptions">Openfaas on Kubernetes - cheapest options</h1>
<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/cost-lite-cluster-month.png" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"><p><strong>update(3 Sep 2018)</strong> : updated installing openfaas on local kube part.</p>
<p><strong>Update(26 Aug 2018)</strong> : I talked with Alex. He told me, &quot;A single node on DigitalOcean with 4GB RAM should be quite cost effective, same with Scaleway using kubeadm. Minikube on your own system is also a good option or with Docker for Mac. (EKS is not cheap) - GKE might be one of the cheaper managed options&quot;</p>
<p>There are many options to use openfaas. Mainly, docker swarm or kubernetes. Kubernetes formed into <a href="https://www.cncf.io/">Cloud Native Computing Foundation</a>. They also have <a href="https://github.com/cncf/curriculum">exam materials</a> for <a href="https://github.com/walidshaari/Kubernetes-Certified-Administrator">certified admin</a> / dev. There are still lots of companies out there using docker swarm as their container orchestration tool. But the trend clearly shows us that kubernetes won the battle. CNCF is the result. It's explicit and configurable. But the problem is installing and maintaining kubernetes on AWS is quite complicated. it takes some time to get used to all setup. With digitalocean, it's fairly easy compare to aws. And after september of 2018, they would release kubernetes as a service. At this point, the pricing page is not there. They might charge it based on droplets.</p>
<p>Then, what would be the optiono to get used to openfaas on kubernetes without spending any money? There are 2 options. local setup and ibm cloud. There are pros and cons. With local setup, it will eat up your resource. And you would not be able to show what you've been playing to other people. As long as you have enough resource, then this is ok. With IBM cloud, you need to switch to pay as you go plan. basically, you need to give them your credit card number. but the &quot;lite&quot; plan doesn't charge you for it. 4GB ram. and it expires in a month. And you can't use ingress. just NodePort. Public IP exists.</p>
<p>The ugly part of serverless thingy is the hidden cost as described <a href="https://medium.com/coryodaniel/from-erverless-to-elixir-48752db4d7bc">here</a>. Openfaas can limit the maximum cost while having the scalability. You have the control. No vendor lock in.</p>
<h2 id="option1openfaasonlocalkuberneres">Option1. Openfaas on local kuberneres</h2>
<p>I assume you're using OS X.</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">brew install kubernetes-cli
brew install kubectx
</code></pre>
<p>Install kubernetes and dashboard by following this <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/dashboard/wiki/Accessing-Dashboard---1.7.X-and-above#api-server">github wiki page</a></p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">kubectl config set-context docker-for-desktop
kubectl config use-context docker-for-desktop
kubectx
kubectl get all
kubectl cluster-info
kubectl create -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubernetes/dashboard/master/src/deploy/recommended/kubernetes-dashboard.yaml

kubectl describe services kubernetes-dashboard --namespace=kube-system
kubectl -n kube-system edit service kubernetes-dashboard
# edit .spec.type to NodePort
sudo kubectl proxy
</code></pre>
<p>visit <a href="http://localhost:8001/api/v1/namespaces/kube-system/services/https:kubernetes-dashboard:/proxy/">the local dashboard</a></p>
<p>get your token to login to the dashboard</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">kubectl create serviceaccount jaigouk
kubectl get serviceaccounts jaigouk -o yaml
apiVersion: v1
kind: ServiceAccount
metadata:
  # ...
secrets:
- name: jaigouk-token-1yvwg
kubectl get secret jaigouk-token-6dztl -o yaml

echo xxxxx== | base64 --decode
</code></pre>
<p>install openfaas</p>
<p>The faas-netes controller is the most tested, stable and supported version of the OpenFaaS integration with Kubernetes. In contrast the OpenFaaS Operator is based upon the codebase and features from faas-netes, but offers a tighter integration with Kubernetes through CustomResourceDefinitions. This means you can type in kubectl get functions for instance.</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openfaas/faas-netes/master/namespaces.yml

helm repo add openfaas https://openfaas.github.io/faas-netes/

helm repo update \
 &amp;&amp; helm upgrade openfaas --install openfaas/openfaas \
    --namespace openfaas  \
    --set functionNamespace=openfaas-fn \
    --set operator.create=true

# generate a random password
export GW_PASS=$(head -c 16 /dev/random |shasum | cut -d ' ' -f1)

kubectl -n openfaas create secret generic basic-auth \
--from-literal=basic-auth-user=admin \
--from-literal=basic-auth-password=$GW_PASS

helm upgrade --reuse-values openfaas openfaas/openfaas \
    --set basic_auth=true

# verify it's running
kubectl --namespace=openfaas get deployments -l &quot;release=openfaas, app=openfaas&quot;

kubectl proxy

echo $GW_PASS | faas-cli login --gateway=&quot;127.0.0.1:31112&quot; -u admin --password-stdin
</code></pre>
<p>visit <a href="http://localhost:31112/ui/">http://localhost:31112/ui/</a><br>
username is admin and password is $GW_PASS value</p>
<p>if you have trouble, visit <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas-netes/blob/master/chart/openfaas/README.md">https://github.com/openfaas/faas-netes/blob/master/chart/openfaas/README.md</a> for details</p>
<h2 id="option2usingkubernetesonibmcloud">Option2. Using kubernetes on IBM cloud</h2>
<p>the IBM cloud gives us free 1 node kubernetes instance that expires in a month. As long as you automated everything then, it wouldn't be a big problem to play with it. For example, you can try <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WYyonInGNsw">&quot;GitLab + OpenFaaS for Serverless CI/CD on Kubernetes&quot;</a>. Check their free versus stand plan features from <a href="https://console.bluemix.net/docs/containers/cs_why.html#cluster_types">this doc</a>.</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh"># Download and install a few CLI tools and the IBM Kubernetes Service plug-in.

curl -sL https://ibm.biz/idt-installer | bash
ibmcloud login -a https://api.eu-de.bluemix.net
ibmcloud cs region-set eu-central
ibmcloud cs cluster-config gunship

export KUBECONFIG=/Users/$USER/.bluemix/plugins/container-service/clusters/gunship/kube-config-mil01-gunship.yml

kubectl get nodes
</code></pre>
<p>let's deploy openfaas.</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">git clone https://github.com/openfaas/faas-netes
# create name space

kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/openfaas/faas-netes/master/namespaces.yml

cd faas-netes &amp;&amp; \kubectl apply -f ./yaml
# memory usage is 327MB
</code></pre>
<p>check your cluster's public ip. visit kubernetes dashboard and find the openfaas namespace. in <code>Discovery and load balancing &gt; Services &gt; gateway</code>, you will be able to see port that is exposed.</p>
<p>running 2x4(2 CPUs, 4 GB RAM, 100 GB HDD) cluster costs $77.76 for 744 hours(31 days). it's worth waiting for digital ocean's kubernetes solution at this point.</p>
<pre><code class="language-sh">brew install kubernetes-helm
helm init --canary-image --upgrade
</code></pre>
<hr>
<h2 id="usefultools">Useful tools</h2>
<h3 id="krex">krex</h3>
<p>Kubernetes Resource Explorer</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kris-nova/krex">https://github.com/kris-nova/krex</a></p>
<p>krex in action - tail logs<br>
<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/krex-in-action1.gif" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"></p>
<p>krex in action - describe &amp; tail logs<br>
<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/krex-in-action2.gif" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"></p>
<p>krex in action - sh into pod<br>
<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/krex-in-action3.gif" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"></p>
<pre><code class="language-sh"># installing
brew install ncurses
export PKG_CONFIG_PATH=/usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig

ln -s /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/formw.pc /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/form.pc
ln -s /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/menuw.pc /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/menu.pc
ln -s /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/panelw.pc /usr/local/opt/ncurses/lib/pkgconfig/panel.pc

go get -u github.com/kris-nova/krex
cd $GOPATH/src/github.com/kris-nova/krex
make all
</code></pre>
<h3 id="kubectx">kubectx</h3>
<p>Fast way to switch between clusters and namespaces in kubectl</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ahmetb/kubectx">https://github.com/ahmetb/kubectx</a></p>
<p>kubectx in action</p>
<p><img src="https://github.com/ahmetb/kubectx/raw/master/img/kubectx-demo.gif" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"></p>
<p>kubens in action</p>
<p><img src="https://github.com/ahmetb/kubectx/raw/master/img/kubens-demo.gif" alt="OpenFaaS on IBM Cloud"></p>
<pre><code class="language-sh"># installing
brew install kubectx
</code></pre>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Running OpenFaaS on Tinkerboard cluster]]></title><description><![CDATA[serverless architecture, microservice, tinker board, OpenFaaS, golang, homelab server]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/openfaas-on-tinkerboard-cluster/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f7f</guid><category><![CDATA[devops]]></category><category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 16:15:15 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/tinker-boards-cluster.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/tinker-boards-cluster.jpg" alt="Running OpenFaaS on Tinkerboard cluster"><p>I wanted to play with serverless architecture but I didn't want to spend money before I get used to the concept. 1 year ago, I tried to do that and ended up using all credits on aws. What would be the cheaper way to learn it? I have been exploring the options. rpi is good but it only has 1GB ram. And then, I encountered asus tinker board. So, I gave it a shot. I bought 3 tinker boards(ARM-Cortex-A17 4x 1.8GHz, 2GB RAM, WLAN, Bluetooth) and 32GB sd cards and etc. I spend 303 euros.</p>
<p>I followed Karol Stepniewski's <a href="http://blog.kars7e.io/2018/01/14/Kubernetes-cluster-on-ARM-using-Asus-Tinkerboard/?utm_content=buffer69682&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">blog post</a> and <a href="https://github.com/jaigouk/tinker-cluster">forked his repo</a>. I used latest armbian image and Network part was fine opposed to his blog post.</p>
<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DWKzLBUXkAIBsUf.jpg:large" alt="Running OpenFaaS on Tinkerboard cluster"></p>
<p>Now, it's time to dig into OpenFaaS.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SwRjPiqpFTk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe> ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[raspberry pi zero w for IOT dev env]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is a first part to build a BLE based physical web prototype app.(elixir, nerves-project, physical web, progressive web, IoT, raspberry pi zero w)]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/raspberry-pi-zero-w-for-iot-dev-env/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f7e</guid><category><![CDATA[elixir]]></category><category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 22:22:56 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/blink.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="motivation">Motivation</h3>
<img src="https://files.jaigouk.com/2018/08/blink.jpg" alt="raspberry pi zero w for IOT dev env"><p>Recently, I watched google i/o tech talks and I found that progressive web + physical web is quite interesting. I had an idea that i want to play with Bluetooth Low Energy devices. For prototying the idea, I bought a raspberry pi zero w. (yup. this is my second one). Before watching the techtalk, rpi0 meant nothing to me. Because I always wanted to have  powerful small computers that I can make a cluster. Now, it makes sense to play with rpi0w. it's a good fit for me to play with it to prototype physical web related ideas.</p>
<h3 id="prep">prep</h3>
<ul>
<li>install virtualbox and ubuntu. prepare your disk that is larger than 16GB if it's a desktop version of ubuntu.</li>
<li>docker should be up and running locally</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="tldr">tl;dr</h3>
<p>In your <code>mix.exs</code> add <code>rpi0_ble</code></p>
<pre><code> def deps(&quot;rpi0&quot;) do
    [{:nerves_runtime, &quot;~&gt; 0.1.0&quot;},
     {:&quot;nerves_system_rpi0_ble&quot;, github: &quot;jaigouk/nerves_system_rpi0_ble&quot;, tag: &quot;v0.0.4&quot;, runtime: false},
     {:nerves_interim_wifi, &quot;~&gt; 0.1.0&quot;}]
  end
</code></pre>
<p>burn your sdcard with following commands.</p>
<pre><code>MIX_TARGET=rpi0 mix deps.get
MIX_TARGET=rpi0 mix firmware
#Burn to an SD card with 
MIX_TARGET=rpi0 mix firmware.burn
</code></pre>
<p>the image has <code>iptables, ssh, erlang, node.js, bluez, git, vi, etc</code>. Because it's for prototyping a ble app and testing it.</p>
<h3 id="configuretheimage">configure the image</h3>
<p>I need to customize the default rpi0 because i need to add bluez. I found <a href="https://learn.adafruit.com/install-bluez-on-the-raspberry-pi/overview">this tutorial</a> from adafruit. Since <a href="http://nerves-project.org/">nerves-project</a> is using <a href="https://buildroot.org">buildroot</a>, there must be a way to add the libarary to my rpi0. And then I found <a href="https://delog.wordpress.com/2014/10/29/bluetooth-on-raspberry-pi-with-buildroot/">this blog post</a></p>
<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/C8SMgSYXkAATESg.jpg" alt="raspberry pi zero w for IOT dev env"></p>
<p>I referenced <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/joelbyler/nerves-plus-phoenix-saves-a-fathers-sanity">this slide</a> and getting started doc from nerves-project.</p>
<p>install and download libraries we need</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">sudo apt-get install git g++ libssl-dev libncurses5-dev bc m4 make unzip cmake
git clone git@github.com:nerves-project/nerves-system-br.git
git clone git@github.com:jaigouk/nerves_system_rpi0_ble.git
mkdir -p ~/.nerves/cache/buildroot
nerves_system_br/create-build.sh nerves_system_rpi0_ble/nerves_defconfig ~/.nerves/cache/buildroot
cd ~/.nerves/cache/buildroot
</code></pre>
<p>Now, let's configure our linux image.</p>
<ul>
<li>Select base packages by running <code>make menuconfig</code></li>
<li>Modify the Linux kernel and kernel modules with <code>make linux-menuconfig</code></li>
<li>Enable more command line utilities using <code>make busybox-menuconfig</code></li>
</ul>
<p><code>make menuconfig</code> will launch gui that helps you to add extra packages. I want to add <code>iptables, git</code></p>
<pre><code>│ Prompt: git
│   Location:
│     -&gt; Target packages
│       -&gt; Development tools
</code></pre>
<p>iptables</p>
<pre><code>│ Prompt: iptables
│   Location:
│     -&gt; Target packages
│       -&gt; Networking applications
</code></pre>
<p>open ssh</p>
<pre><code>│ Prompt: openssh
│   Location:
│     -&gt; Target packages
│       -&gt; Networking applications
</code></pre>
<p>openssl</p>
<pre><code> Prompt: openssl
│   Location:
│     -&gt; Target packages
│       -&gt; Libraries
│         -&gt; Crypto
</code></pre>
<p>you can even find <code>nginx, wireshark,etc</code> in networking applications.</p>
<p>Run <code>make savedefconfig</code> after <code>make menuconfig</code> to update the nerves_defconfig in your System. it will spit out results like this.</p>
<pre><code>umask 0022 &amp;&amp; make -C /home/jaigouk/nerves_system_br/buildroot-2016.11.1 O=/home/jaigouk/.nerves/cache/buildroot/. savedefconfig
  GEN     /home/jaigouk/.nerves/cache/buildroot/Makefile
</code></pre>
<p><code>linux-menuconfig</code></p>
<pre><code>│ Prompt: Bluetooth Low Energy (LE) features
│   Location:
│     -&gt; Networking support (NET [=y])
│       -&gt; Bluetooth subsystem support (BT [=y])
</code></pre>
<p>Run <code>make linux-savedefconfig</code> and <code>cp build/linux-x.y.z/defconfig &lt;your system&gt;</code></p>
<pre><code>umask 0022 &amp;&amp; make -C /home/jaigouk/nerves_system_br/buildroot-2016.11.1 O=/home/jaigouk/.nerves/cache/buildroot/. linux-savedefconfig
</code></pre>
<p>we can add <code>vim, grep, ifconfig, ping, ps, top, free, etc</code> with following command. busybox-menuconfig only works when busybox is enabled.</p>
<pre><code>make busybox-menuconfig
</code></pre>
<p>this is what getstarted doc says.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If your system doesn’t contain a custom Linux configuration yet, you’ll need to update the Buildroot configuration to point to the new Linux defconfig in your system directory. The path is usually something like <code>$( )/linux-x.y_defconfig</code>.<br>
For Busybox, the convention is to copy <code>build/busybox-x.y.z/.config</code> to a file in the System repository. Like the Linux configuration, the Buildroot configuration will need to be updated to point to the custom config.</p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>/home/jaigouk/.nerves/cache/buildroot/build/busybox-1.25.1/.config
</code></pre>
<p>So I copied <code>defconfig</code> to <code>nerves_system_rpi0_ble/linux-4.4.defconfig</code> and <code>.config</code> to <code>nerves_system_rpi0_ble/nerves_defconfig</code></p>
<p>now my custom rpi0 config is ready to be used.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[In Berlin]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I moved to Berlin 1 month ago. I was curious what it's like to be in startup eco in Berlin. As a Korean, I heard good things about it. Lots of game companies and devs moved to Germany from South Korea for lots of reasons.</p>
<p>I talked with my colleagues</p>]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/in-berlin/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f7c</guid><category><![CDATA[life]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 23:10:26 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/cdn.jaigouk.com/blog-images/berlin.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/cdn.jaigouk.com/blog-images/berlin.jpg" alt="In Berlin"><p>I moved to Berlin 1 month ago. I was curious what it's like to be in startup eco in Berlin. As a Korean, I heard good things about it. Lots of game companies and devs moved to Germany from South Korea for lots of reasons.</p>
<p>I talked with my colleagues in Berlin. U.S is not an ideal place for asian tech people to stay any more. Well, especially in these days, Trump is making it worse day by day. On HN, I saw an article that says tech companies in Silicon Valley started to think about relocating to Vancouver. The news about immigrants in U.S is familiar to me. Because I also have gone through those situations when I visited U.S before.</p>
<p>I hope wealth is more distributed by new political actions. Otherwise, people will not be able to contain their anger.</p>
<p>Anyways, it has been 1 month in Berlin now. I hope I can meet lots of awesome hackers here.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[reactjs]]></title><description><![CDATA[react.js, frontend]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/reactjs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f76</guid><category><![CDATA[frontend]]></category><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 19:53:41 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/macbook-closed.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/macbook-closed.jpeg" alt="reactjs"><p class="subtitle">
Learn once, write anywhere
</p>
<h4 id="motivationtostickwithit">Motivation to stick with it</h4>
<p>I picked up ruby language in 2008 and I fell in love with it. The philosophy was &quot;Programming languages must feel natural to programmers.&quot; instead of hammering my head to figure out how to write codes in proper way. And that sparked various open source projects. I see the similar thing is happening in JS community. Lots of mobile devs are suffering because of iOS / Angular. React Native is trying to tackle that problem.</p>
<blockquote>
It's worth noting that we're not chasing “write once, run anywhere.” Different platforms have different looks, feels, and capabilities, and as such, we should still be developing discrete apps for each platform, but the same set of engineers should be able to build applications for whatever platform they choose, without needing to learn a fundamentally different set of technologies for each. We call this approach “learn once, write anywhere.”
<cite>— Tom Occhino, "React Native: Bringing modern web techniques to mobile", Facebook Code Blog, (Mar. 26, 2015)</cite></blockquote>
<p>It's expanding beyond web and mobile. VR is the next thing they are working on now.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/react-vr.png" alt="reactjs"></p>
<h4 id="resources">Resources</h4>
<p><a href="http://reactjsprogram.com/">http://reactjsprogram.com/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/transistorsoft/react-native-background-fetch">https://github.com/transistorsoft/react-native-background-fetch</a></p>
<p>vr related - <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/vr-developer-nanodegree--nd017">https://www.udacity.com/course/vr-developer-nanodegree--nd017</a></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></title><description><![CDATA[blockchain, microservice, devops, ideas]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/blockchain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f75</guid><category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 03:45:56 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/universe.jpeg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/universe.jpeg" alt="Blockchain"><p class="subtitle">
the power shift from platforms to people would happen anytime soon.
</p>
<p>Mediachain or OpenBazaar like new market place will be arrived. I am gathering resources to track that change.</p>
<h4 id="books">Books</h4>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Blockchain-Revolution-Technology-Changing-Business/dp/1511357673">Blockchain Revolution</a></p>
<h4 id="videos">Videos</h4>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m1sBurdHCNo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FtR06bIDxkE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RgENsi-qpn4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AllnjW_04Y0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WfULutvxvzY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6_jacBtTuNs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<h4 id="opensources">Opensources</h4>
<div class="github-card" data-user="blockchain" data-repo="thunder"></div>
<div class="github-card" data-user="ipfs" data-repo="ipfs"></div>
<div class="github-card" data-user="igorbarinov" data-repo="awesome-blockchain"></div>
<script src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/js/github-cards.js"></script>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Running Deis on AWS]]></title><description><![CDATA[deploymenent, deis, kubernetes, naked domain with cloud flare]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/running-deis-on-aws/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f74</guid><category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category><category><![CDATA[devops]]></category><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 02:09:12 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/coffee-coding-512w.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/coffee-coding-512w.png" alt="Running Deis on AWS"><p class="subtitle">
(Deis + Kubernetes + AWS) for the win
</p>
<p>I like to use deis because I can deploy my projects just like heroku while I can play with kubernetes. So I setup deis on aws. I wanted to use http2 and I can't use http2 ports on heroku.</p>
<p>3 Steps</p>
<ol>
<li>deploy kubernetes with <a href="https://github.com/kz8s/tack">tack</a></li>
<li>install deis with helmc</li>
<li>setup DNS and Letsencrypt certs</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="tack">tack</h4>
<p>I used <a href="https://github.com/kz8s/tack">https://github.com/kz8s/tack</a> for setting up kubernetes on AWS.</p>
<ol>
<li>check <code>~/.aws/config</code> region</li>
<li>change name of region in <code>Makefile</code> after running <code>make clean</code></li>
<li>if kubectl is not working, check the path of <code>tack/.cfssl</code> or <code>tack/.keypair</code></li>
<li>in <code>io.tf</code> you can change kubernetes version. visit &quot;quay.io/coreos/hyperkube&quot; and check the latest tag.</li>
<li>in <code>~/.kube/config</code>, there would be settings for previous builds.</li>
<li>check <code>~/.helmc</code> and delete cache and workspace folders. (in case you changed the path of <code>tack</code>)</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="deis">Deis</h4>
<p>we are gong to use <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/helm">Helm</a> to manage packages for kubernetes.</p>
<pre><code>curl -sSL http://deis.io/deis-cli/install-v2.sh | bash
mv deis /usr/local/bin
curl -sSL https://get.helm.sh | bash

mv $PWD/helmc /usr/local/bin/helmc
helmc target # Ensure the kubectl client is installed and 
			 # can connect to your Kubernetes cluster.
</code></pre>
<p>CAUTION. UPDATE ROLES TO worker and master role. then visit <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/home?region=ap-southeast-1#roles">https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/home?region=ap-southeast-1#roles</a>. Add ec2, rds, s3, ecs roles to worker .</p>
<p>if you want to change config for workflow, check deis-s3-db-registry folder</p>
<pre><code>helmc fetch deis/workflow-v2.7.0            # fetches the chart into a
											# local workspace
</code></pre>
<p>At this point, You may want to configure s3 and postgres for deis.<br>
<a href="https://deis.com/docs/workflow/installing-workflow/configuring-postgres/">https://deis.com/docs/workflow/installing-workflow/configuring-postgres/</a></p>
<p>On aws, after creating the postgres db, add a inboud rule to the security group like this so that local machine or deis can connect to it.</p>
<pre><code>Security Group Rules - Edit inbound rules
TCP 5432 Anywhere 0.0.0.0/0
</code></pre>
<p>For s3, Ater creating 3 bukcets, you need to add more permission to the IAM role. visit <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/home?region=ap-southeast-1#roles">https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/home?region=ap-southeast-1#roles</a> and add s3 related permissions to worker-k8s-rpc, master-k8s-rpc<br>
currently, I am not using ecr for registry. For custom domains, you may want to add route53 related permissions to those roles too.</p>
<p>If you want to use ecr then visit <a href="https://ap-southeast-1.console.aws.amazon.com/ecs/home?region=ap-southeast-1#/firstRun">https://ap-southeast-1.console.aws.amazon.com/ecs/home?region=ap-southeast-1#/firstRun</a> and setup cluster then change the <code>~/.helmc/workspace/charts/workflow-v2.7.0/tpl/generate_params.toml</code> file.</p>
<p>change s3 or rds related config before you run <code>generate</code></p>
<pre><code>helmc generate -x manifests workflow-v2.7.0 # generates various secrets
helmc install workflow-v2.7.0               # injects resources into
											# your cluster
kubectl --namespace=deis get pods #-&gt; should return more than 10 pods
</code></pre>
<p>Configure your AWS Load Balancer for <code>git push</code>. Set the timeout to 3600.<br>
<a href="https://deis.com/docs/workflow/managing-workflow/configuring-load-balancers/">configuring a load balancer¶</a></p>
<pre><code>kubectl --namespace=deis annotate deployment/deis-router router.deis.io/nginx.useProxyProtocol=true

 kubectl --namespace=deis annotate service/deis-router service.beta.kubernetes.io/aws-load-balancer-proxy-protocol='*'
</code></pre>
<p>and then register to your server</p>
<pre><code>
deis register http://deis.example.com
admin / ****** 
</code></pre>
<p>add ssh <code>deis keys:add</code>. For setting up DNS records, check the following section.</p>
<h4 id="nakeddomainforadeisproject">Naked domain for a deis project</h4>
<p>I have several domains for projects. let’s say 2 for deis hub and 1 for my project. Assume that example.com is our project and root.io and root.co are my hub domains. I am using AWS and Cloudflare to achieve naked domain.</p>
<p>add domains to the repo</p>
<pre><code>  deis domains:add example.com
  deis domains:add www.example.com
  deis domains:add unbent-backbone.root.io
</code></pre>
<p>add a url forwarding page rule: match &quot;www.example.com/*&quot; with &quot;<a href="https://example.com/$1">https://example.com/$1</a>&quot;</p>
<pre><code>  # DNS Setup for example.com on cloudflare
  CNAME www             unbent-backbone.root.io  (orange)
  CNAME @               unbent-backbone.root.io  (orange)

  # DNS Setup for root.io on cloudflare
  CNAME @               hub.root.co      (!! NO ORANGE)
  CNAME deis            hub.root.co      (orange)
  CNAME deis-builder    hub.root.co      (!! NO ORANGE)
  CNAME unbent-backbone hub.root.co      (orange)
</code></pre>
<p>setup the alias for elb</p>
<pre><code>  # DNS Setup for root.co on AWS Route53
  A hub.root.co Alias Target dualstack.xxx.ap-southeast-1.elb.amazonaws.com
</code></pre>
<h4 id="letsencrypt">Letsencrypt</h4>
<ol>
<li>do nothing for aws elb</li>
<li>use cloudflare for https assets</li>
<li>use <code>kube-cert-manager</code>.based on <a href="https://github.com/PalmStoneGames/kube-cert-manager">https://github.com/PalmStoneGames/kube-cert-manager</a>, it works. I just had to change <code>psg</code> to my domain in the project files. and build <code>kube-cert-manager</code>executable file. And then I build the docker image and published it.</li>
</ol>
<h4 id="uninstallreinstall">Uninstall / Reinstall</h4>
<p>if you are going to reinstall, do not delete elb.</p>
<pre><code>	cd .helmc
	helmc uninstall workflow-v2.7.0 -n deis
	cd tack
	make clean
</code></pre>
<p>check vpc, elb, s3 buckets<br>
change the name of instance in tack's Makefile<br>
before install, check to regions in ~/.aws/ and ~/.deis and tack's Make file<br>
or any ENV vars. ~/.zsh_aliase has ENV var to access AWS!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[grpc]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="subtitle">
The ultimate glue for microservices
</p>
<p>I am playing with grpc on kubernetes in these days. My starting point is<br>
<a href="https://jaigouk.com/grpc/github.com/thesandlord/nginx-kubernetes-lb">nginx-kubernets-lb</a>. I wanted to start from small and light solution. But heroku was not an option to play with this. So I had to setup kubernetes on aws. I deployed <code>Deis</code></p>]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/grpc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f72</guid><category><![CDATA[posts]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 21:50:07 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/blink.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cdn.jaigouk.com/2016/10/blink.jpg" alt="grpc"><p class="subtitle">
The ultimate glue for microservices
</p>
<p>I am playing with grpc on kubernetes in these days. My starting point is<br>
<a href="https://jaigouk.com/grpc/github.com/thesandlord/nginx-kubernetes-lb">nginx-kubernets-lb</a>. I wanted to start from small and light solution. But heroku was not an option to play with this. So I had to setup kubernetes on aws. I deployed <code>Deis</code> too. It took some time to be able to reproduce the production env. This blog is also running on kubernetes. Now, I am ready to play!</p>
<h4 id="mainresources">main resources</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.grpc.io/">http://www.grpc.io/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/grpc/">https://github.com/grpc/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>videos - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLcTqM9n_dieM6M4lgL9qdu-UridiVe8Gx">https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLcTqM9n_dieM6M4lgL9qdu-UridiVe8Gx</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>gRPC: The Story of Microservices at Square -&gt; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2sWDr3Z0Wo">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-2sWDr3Z0Wo</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Real-time IoT with Containers and gRPC (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nz-LcdoMYWA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nz-LcdoMYWA</a> ) (<a href="https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/grpc-simon-says">https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/grpc-simon-says</a>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesandlord/samples/tree/master/grpc-kubernetes-microservices">https://github.com/thesandlord/samples/tree/master/grpc-kubernetes-microservices</a> , video : <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UOIJNygDNlE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UOIJNygDNlE</a>, slide: <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/thesandlord/building-scalable-microservices-with-kubernetes-grpc-and-containers-api-world-2015">https://speakerdeck.com/thesandlord/building-scalable-microservices-with-kubernetes-grpc-and-containers-api-world-2015</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Creating a scalable API with microservices(<a href="https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/06/creating-a-scalable-API-with-microservices.html">https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/06/creating-a-scalable-API-with-microservices.html</a>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Kelsey Hightower - Building Microservices with gRPC and Kubernetes (<a href="http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/86187859">http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/86187859</a>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://dbeck.github.io/5-lessons-learnt-from-choosing-zeromq-and-protobuf/">http://dbeck.github.io/5-lessons-learnt-from-choosing-zeromq-and-protobuf/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://blog.jonharrington.org/elixir-and-czmq/">http://blog.jonharrington.org/elixir-and-czmq/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/jbavari/elixir-zeromq-protobuf-uploader">https://github.com/jbavari/elixir-zeromq-protobuf-uploader</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="caution">caution</h4>
<ul>
<li>ruby gem - download  ruby gem instead of installing grpc</li>
<li>heroku - not suitable for grace. heroku does not support http2. grpc needs that.(<a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/http-routing">https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/http-routing</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="deploy">deploy</h4>
<p><a href="https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/08/gRPC-a-true-Internet-scale-RPC-framework-is-now-1-and-ready-for-production-deployments.html">https://cloudplatform.googleblog.com/2016/08/gRPC-a-true-Internet-scale-RPC-framework-is-now-1-and-ready-for-production-deployments.html</a></p>
<h5 id="1ruby">1. ruby</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.grpc.io/docs/quickstart/ruby.html">http://www.grpc.io/docs/quickstart/ruby.html</a></p>
<h5 id="2nodejs">2. node.js</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.grpc.io/docs/quickstart/node.html">http://www.grpc.io/docs/quickstart/node.html</a></p>
<h5 id="3elixir">3. elixir</h5>
<p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/tony612/the-way-to-grpc-elixir">https://speakerdeck.com/tony612/the-way-to-grpc-elixir</a><br>
<a href="https://github.com/tony612/grpc-elixir">https://github.com/tony612/grpc-elixir</a></p>
<h5 id="heroku">heroku</h5>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kyleconroy/heroku-buildpack-grpc">https://github.com/kyleconroy/heroku-buildpack-grpc</a></p>
<h5 id="polyglot">polyglot</h5>
<p><a href="https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/polyglot">https://github.com/grpc-ecosystem/polyglot</a></p>
<p>Polyglot is a grpc client which can talk to any grpc server. In order to make a call, the following are required:</p>
<ul>
<li>A compiled Polyglot binary,</li>
<li>the .proto files for the service,</li>
<li>and a request proto instance in text format.</li>
</ul>
<p>In particular, it is not necessary to generate grpc classes for the service or to compile the protos into the Polyglot binary.</p>
<ul>
<li>Supports unary, client streaming, server streaming, and bidi streaming rpcs.</li>
<li>Runs on Windows, Mac and Linux.</li>
<li>Parses proto files at runtime to discover services. Supports pretty-printing discovered services.</li>
<li>Supports authentication via oauth.</li>
<li>Accepts request protos through stdin and can output responses to stdout to allow chaining.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[reboot]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p class="subtitle">
Stack : deis, kubernetes, gitlab, node.js, ruby, elixir, react + redux
</p>
<p>I am starting another blog here.</p>]]></description><link>https://jaigouk.com/reboot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b7b254eb697ec0020092f73</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaigouk Kim]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 09:30:05 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://jaigouk.com/content/images/2018/04/sakura-2.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://jaigouk.com/content/images/2018/04/sakura-2.jpg" alt="reboot"><p class="subtitle">
Stack : deis, kubernetes, gitlab, node.js, ruby, elixir, react + redux
</p>
<p>I am starting another blog here.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>