<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Stories by Sehyeon  Nam on Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Stories by Sehyeon  Nam on Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/0*AbuMhXbmvdnHHAaC.</url>
            <title>Stories by Sehyeon  Nam on Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 20:26:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/@Nam_se" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[리액트에 타입스크립트를 얹느냐 안얹느냐 그것이 문제로다… 구글링 하니까 형 글이 나오네요 ㅋㅋ]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/%EB%A6%AC%EC%95%A1%ED%8A%B8%EC%97%90-%ED%83%80%EC%9E%85%EC%8A%A4%ED%81%AC%EB%A6%BD%ED%8A%B8%EB%A5%BC-%EC%96%B9%EB%8A%90%EB%83%90-%EC%95%88%EC%96%B9%EB%8A%90%EB%83%90-%EA%B7%B8%EA%B2%83%EC%9D%B4-%EB%AC%B8%EC%A0%9C%EB%A1%9C%EB%8B%A4-%EA%B5%AC%EA%B8%80%EB%A7%81-%ED%95%98%EB%8B%88%EA%B9%8C-%ED%98%95-%EA%B8%80%EC%9D%B4-%EB%82%98%EC%98%A4%EB%84%A4%EC%9A%94-%E3%85%8B%E3%85%8B-fd99d43520c1?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/fd99d43520c1</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 08:40:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-05-27T08:40:50.932Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>리액트에 타입스크립트를 얹느냐 안얹느냐 그것이 문제로다… 구글링 하니까 형 글이 나오네요 ㅋㅋ</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=fd99d43520c1" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jend-To-Kend D-1]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/jend-to-kend-d-1-80b1a731154?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/80b1a731154</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 21:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-09-16T21:28:37.359Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>여행 일지를 쓰면 좋을 것 같다는 생각이 들었다. 매일 성실하게 쓸 수 있을진 자신이 없지만 이왕 쓰기로 했으므로 오늘부터 써본다.</p><p>여행 타이틀은 Jend To Kend다. Jend는 Japan + End, Kend는 Korea + End다. 일본 끝에서 한국 끝까지 여행하는 것이기 때문이다. 일본 홋카이도에서 도쿄, 오사카, 후쿠오카를 지나 배 타고 부산을 가서 서울까지 올라가는 여정이다.</p><p>이 모든 여정을 자전거와 함께한다. 대략 40일 정도가 걸리지 않을까 싶다.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*PIoDlnrpf2lm925VWkWv-w.jpeg" /><figcaption>자전거를 이 박스에 넣어 수화물로 보낸다. 왼쪽 위 손잡이 구멍이 찢어져서 구멍이 커졌다.</figcaption></figure><p>원래는 오늘(2017년 9월 17일 일요일)은 진작에 일본에 있어야 했다. 엊그제인 금요일에 출발하기로 계획을 세웠기 때문이다. 하지만 Wifi 라우터를 제때 예약하지 않아서 일정을 미루게 되었다.</p><p>Wifi 라우터에 신경을 쓰는 이유는 이 여행을 Twitch에서 방송할 것이기 때문이다. 덕분에 방송이 가능한 카메라를 구매하느라 돈을 꽤 많이 썼다.</p><p>왜 방송을 하려고 하는가? 글쎄? 나도 잘 모른다. 그냥 재미있을 것 같아서 그렇게 하기로 했다. 꼭 무슨 특별한 이유가 있어야 할까? 재미있어서 정도면 충분할 것 같다.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*ONmUJMy5P--EpRCgSvQktw.jpeg" /><figcaption>왼쪽은 핸들바 가방, 위쪽은 안장 가방이다. 방송때문에 장비가 많아서 가방을 추가로 더 구할걸 그랬나 후회한다.</figcaption></figure><p>나는 요 며칠 동안 자기관리를 제대로 못하고 있다. 진작에 예약하고 알아봤으면 제 때 여행을 갈 수 있었을 텐데… 이 모든 것은 내 잘못이라고 생각한다. 문제는 이 자책이 점점 심해지면서 내 자신이 나를 함부로 대하기 시작한다는 것이다. 오늘만 보더라도 진작에 아침부터 마무리 준비를 했어야 했는데, 어제 새벽까지 게임한다고 깨어있고, 오늘도 게임한다고 낮에 준비를 못했다.</p><p>이런 내가 나는 매우 싫다.</p><p>여행을 잘 마무리 할 수 있을지 의문이 든다. 자전거 타고 가는 것 자체는 문제가 없어보인다. 하지만 내가 그 여정을 전부 카메라에 담아서 방송으로 실시간으로 송출할 수 있을지 의심이 많이 든다. 출퇴근 하면서 테스트 방송을 하긴 했지만 상황은 매우 달라질 것이다. 여러모로 스트레스가 쌓인다.</p><p>그래서 요 며칠 전부터 입버릇으로 나는 계속 “아 여행 괜히 가는거 아닌가”라고 혼잣말을 했다.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*zoNZfsuRpPbFFua5WbKI0g.jpeg" /><figcaption>최대 8시간 연속 방송을 한다는 가정 하에 들고가는 배터리와 충전기들</figcaption></figure><p>지금 시각은 오전 6시 25분. 이젠 자야만 한다. 한 2시간 30분정도 자고 9시에 일어나서 바쁘게 인천 공항에 가야한다. 제발 내일 마지막으로 짐을 챙길 때 집에 놓고 가는 물건이 없길 바랄 뿐이다.</p><p>여행 방송은 여기서 한다냥) <a href="https://twitch.tv/namse_">https://twitch.tv/namse_</a><br>아마 아침 9시나 10시부터 시작하지 않을까 싶다.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=80b1a731154" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MVP of Black Mark Down]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/mvp-of-black-mark-down-aed1a20a6e16?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/aed1a20a6e16</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blackmarkdown]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[serverless]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[aws]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 08:28:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-02-11T08:28:15.425Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays I’m making Markdown Publishing Platform named Black Mark Down. Yesterday, I finished making MVP(Minimum Viable Product) of Black Mark Down. Today I’m gonna write what I did and what I will do in this post.</p><h4>1. The Principle of Work — Priority</h4><p>My principle of work on this project is “Do important thing first following priority”. Then, what was the priority for me?</p><p>I plan to use serverless architecture for this project. The most important thing was proving that we can use serverless architecture with AWS or not. I thought we can make markdown editor easily, because it isn’t not big deal. So I set priorities, back-end first, front-end second.</p><h4>2. Implementation of Back-End</h4><p>I started to read all documentation about AWS Cognito, IAM and something else and designed back-end system. I found I can make this project with Cognito, S3, Lambda, and something else, without running EC2 instances.</p><p>I coded a back-end system and also made test codes. It was so great to make a test code for back-end system. If I don’t have a test code, then I maybe have to test myself. That would make me so tired. I swear that.</p><h4>3. Implementation of Front-End</h4><p>I already tested back-end code with test codes that describe all scenario about our front-end. It looks like the same with general users’ actions, just without any UI.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/582/1*5B1N8MKNrYpHymaHt2Dlkw.png" /><figcaption>Test Codes with Mocha.js</figcaption></figure><p>So the only one I have to do is just making UIs following scenarios I thought. I made Sign-up Page, View Page, e.t.c. But I wan’t care about UI styles. because It wan’t on the priority. I wanted to see a possibility first.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/682/1*I2nt5kKRvYvHKkpru0jUmQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>Collection of Pages. Sign-up, Log-in, View my docs, Post new markdown… It works!</figcaption></figure><h3>Sprint &amp; Development Cycle</h3><p>The process I did during last few weeks seems like sprint. Let’s think about development cycle below,</p><p>Design → Modeling → Implementation &amp; Test → Deploy → Feedback</p><p>I deployed this MVP with AWS S3 static web hosting, and I got feedbacks from my friends. Wow, yes, I followed general development cycle!</p><h3>Next Sprint</h3><p>Then, what’s the next sprint? I want to check that we can make awesome editor and viewer or not.<br>I already found that I can store user’s data securely. It means I’m ready to meet users. So, it’s very natural to attract user for next step!</p><h3>“Nice Editor, Awesome Viewer.”</h3><p>It is the main objective of next sprint for us.</p><p>BlackMarkDown Github : <a href="https://github.com/BlackMarkDown/black-mark-down">https://github.com/BlackMarkDown/black-mark-down</a></p><p>Ps. Oh, you know what? there is a domain with ‘.md’! I’m gonna buy ‘readme.md’ domain later for this project. SUPER AWESOME.</p><p>// I’m looking for job opportunities in Canada. I have working permit. please contact me.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=aed1a20a6e16" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AWS API Gateway and Binary Data]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/aws-api-gateway-and-binary-data-6514beb8af81?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6514beb8af81</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blackmarkdown]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[aws]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[aws-lambda]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[aws-api-gateway]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 13:43:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-01-27T13:43:21.948Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was trying to use AWS API Gateway with AWS Lambda to handle RESTful API Request for <a href="https://github.com/BlackMarkDown/black-mark-down">BlackMarkDown Project</a></p><p>To authenticate user’s image uploading, I made Lambda function to handle that. So I sent Image file to API Gateway, and when I found a log on Lambda, that http request’s body was distorted.</p><p>I found that value is encoded with UTF-8, first 3 bytes was EF BB BF. Did I encode image data into UTF-8 before sending?</p><h3>1. Try it in local</h3><p>I tested it in local system. It is generally hard to debug on full-size system. Making environments simple is helpful to debug and concentrate on the exact problem.</p><p>When I tested image uploading in local, it was perfect. the data local server got was raw data, not encoded. Hmm… That mean someone transform my raw data into UTF-8. <strong>The Client Has No guilty!</strong></p><h3>2. Find rumors</h3><p>I had some googling, and I found that API Gateway start to support binary data transfer from November, 2016. Oh, I thought that API Gateway support binary data as default. Why they didn’t support it?</p><p>Anyway, and also to turn on the binary transfer, I should set some options in AWS Console. Yes. I did it. And I restarted testing. Sent http request, got 200 status codes, opened logs. Oh, something changed! I clicked to open uploaded image on S3 storage.</p><p>BUT. I couldn’t open that image file. WHAT THE F-</p><h3>3. Dig DEEP</h3><p>I read and read every documents about API Gateway’s binary transfer. But nothing Let me make this problem clear.</p><p>I found one, When I export my API Gateway settings into JSON files, there were ‘CONVERT_TO_TEXT’. Oh, I got it. API Gateway convert data to text(base64)!</p><p>But there were no way to set that pass through data to Lambda. What? WHAT?</p><h3>4. SURRENDER</h3><p>I tried to set CONVERT_TO_TEXT option into pass thru option with Cloud Formation. But it didn’t work.</p><p>I thought API Gateway dosen’t yet suppport pass raw binary data to lambda. It could be.</p><p>I noticed that I spent too much times to solve this problem. But it was worthy against that times? No… I don’t think so. And also in my system, it’s not big deal that API Gateway convert binary data into base64.</p><p>… … sign…</p><h3>Finally I just let Lambda function decode received data from API Gateway.</h3><p>Have you ever seen the movie, Interstellar? I want to say to myself,</p><blockquote><strong>“STAY… STAY… DO NOT TRY TO FIX IT… JUST DECODE IN LAMBDA AND COVER IT UP…”</strong></blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6514beb8af81" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Mark Down — My New Project]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/black-mark-down-my-new-project-f0b17d9454ab?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f0b17d9454ab</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 12:51:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-01-27T12:51:37.735Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays I’m in “Black Mark Down” project, which is online Mark-down document publishing platform.</p><p>Github : https://github.com/BlackMarkDown/black-mark-down</p><p>Generally programmers love Markdown and they oftenly use it to make Read-Me file. Have you ever seen README.md file in github.com? That extension .md mean it is ‘m’ark’d’own file.</p><p>Markdown is one of the tag, mark-up lamguage like HTML. The origin of name is from opposite of “mark-up”. Ha! Developer’s humor.</p><p>This project has very fun architecture. There are no server that I manage. I just use</p><ul><li>Amazon S3 — Main storage</li><li>AWS API Gateway + AWS Lambda — For server logics</li><li>Amazon DynamoDB — Sub storage</li><li>Amazon Cognito — User authentication</li></ul><p>I don’t have to wake up during sleeping to manage my server! SUPER AWESOME.</p><p>Yes, I was making a game with UE4. But I failed to keep my motivation, and when I wrote my game development blog, I wished writing that blog with markdown.</p><p>After this project, I swear to make my own game.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f0b17d9454ab" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameDevStory 5. <Blink>]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-5-blink-710684aba5ab?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/710684aba5ab</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[unreal-engine]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[game-development]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 05:29:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-01-02T05:29:55.823Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What’s up Medium! Long time no see, isn’t it? :D</p><p>For this a few weeks I was being depressed so I just rested. Actually I applied many company at Canada, but I failed terribly. I wanted to improve myself but I couldn’t get any feedbacks. I was confused myself, it never helped me. That fact made me depressed.</p><p>I thought the main reason why I failed to get job is maybe visa, so I finally get my job(I teach programming to students!) at Korea and still try to get Canada’s working permit.</p><p>Anyway! It is my current state. Let’s go to Blink Skill what I implemented.</p><h3>What is Blink?</h3><p>Blink, blink! blink is the same with teleportation. With blink skill, we can teleport short distance instantly. You can find this skill at LOL, or Tracer of Overwatch.</p><h3>How did I Implement?</h3><p>As you know, I’m developing my game with UE4, especially Blueprint as main. And there’s embeded teleportation function in Blueprint. It supports sweeping to stop movement until it collides other object.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*M-FoGW_4t6JgLHqzQc9LXA.gif" /><figcaption>Sweep. Image from <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/blog/moving-physical-objects">https://www.unrealengine.com/blog/moving-physical-objects</a></figcaption></figure><p>But I don’t want to sweep. I just want to place my character, even if there’re something between origin position and destination. I only consider the objects that near about destination so it could be collided to my character.</p><p>So, let’s arrange what I want to do. The blink skill’s process must be,</p><ol><li>Place my character with teleport function</li><li>If there is other object in destination so it collide with my character,</li><li>SOLVE THIS PROBLEM. DO PLACE YOUR CHARACTER NAHHHHH!!!</li></ol><h3>First attempt: Sweep backward.</h3><p>I check collision at destination. If there’s no collision, it’s good and I just put my character at that location. but, If there’s collision I start sweeping from destination to origin location. It is opposite of UE4’s sweep, they weep from origin to destination.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/313/1*n6mRSj4IV2wfDk7HyJdvGw.png" /><figcaption>Trace collision sweeping the sphere form start to end position.</figcaption></figure><p>But there is problem still. this function couldn’t resolve contiguous objects. It just return the edge of collision. I mean, I couldn’t know during tracing when the collision is exactly end. For example, If there’re the walls contiguously, with this function, my character just teleport to second wall’s edge and be stuck between two wall.</p><h3>Second attempt: Spiral collision checking</h3><p>This skill is motivated from LOL’s skill. I fortunately found how they implemented Blink skill at LOL’s patch note. It wasn’t detailed, but they told they do spiral collision checking.</p><p>I also developed spiral collision checking in my previous version. But I thought this way might be not good because it has bad performance.</p><p>But blink skill has long cool-time and it doesn’t need over a second computing time. So that performance could be ignore-able.</p><p>Here is my pseudo-code,</p><pre>degree = 0;<br>radius = 0;<br>while (true) {<br>  radius += radiusIncrement;<br>  for degree = 0 ~ 360 {<br>    point = destination + radius * Vector(cos(degree), sin(degree));<br>    if (CollisionTest(point)) {<br>      Set Character Position to point.<br>      return;      <br>    }<br>  }<br>}</pre><p>And I trans-coded it to Blueprint. <em>I think it is hard to capture blueprint… it’s too big!</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/684/1*kTaE4xqbL5Xosq2VP8xF8w.png" /><figcaption>Yeah, It has avant-garde shape.</figcaption></figure><h3>Result</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*lBNFY3riiCX2g8qBpHLwSQ.gif" /><figcaption>It work well!</figcaption></figure><p>The white dots is what I printed when I compute collision checking. That point was the center of character in collision checking.</p><p>The sense of accomplishment wasn’t big because I’ve the same experience already, and I spend a lot of time to solve this problem in other way. It was so stressful.</p><h3>What’s the next?</h3><p>I try to reduce the list of TODO to minify my project. Everyone want to make their game bigger, but it’s too hard to make big game at once.</p><p>So I’m rearrange my todo list. That mean, There isn’t no next step not yet :D But maybe the next will be making game rule, the condition checking for end of the game.</p><p><em>I’m looking for a job in Canada. Please check my </em><a href="https://kr.linkedin.com/in/sehyun-nam-85838774"><em>Linked profile </em></a><em>and contact me (skatpgusskat@naver.com).</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=710684aba5ab" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-5-blink-710684aba5ab">GameDevStory 5. &lt;Blink&gt;</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory">GameDevStory</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Serverless Markdown CMS) 1. 청사진]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@Nam_se/serverless-markdown-cms-1-%EC%B2%AD%EC%82%AC%EC%A7%84-f4830bc1aac8?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f4830bc1aac8</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[serverless]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[aws]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[lambda]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cms]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 02:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2016-12-27T02:44:22.445Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Markdown을 사용하는 한국형 Cafe형태의 CMS를 만들게 되었다. 이 글은 Eagle은 아니고 개발 청사진을 정리한 글이다.</p><h3>내가 원하는 것</h3><p>나는</p><ol><li>서버 관리를 하고 싶지 않다</li><li>테스트를 일일이 하고 싶지 않다</li><li>관리자가 알아서 쉽게 관리할 수 있도록 하고 싶다</li><li>서버 유지에 비싼 비용을 들이고 싶지 않다</li></ol><p>그리하여 AWS의 Lambda를 이용한 Serverless 아키텍처면 어느정도 내 니즈를 만족시키리라 본다.</p><p>지금까지 생각해본 전체적인 그림은 내가 직접 AWS 인프라 관리 코드를 짜는게 아니라, Serverless와 그 안에서 제공하는 CloudFormation를 이용하는 것이다.</p><ul><li>ServerLess 프레임워크 이용</li><li>부가적인 관리요소는 CloudFormation 이용</li><li>테스트와 배포는 Travis 사용</li><li>웹서비스지만 Server/Client로 확실히 나눔<br>(React를 이용한 SPA Client, Lambda에서 돌아가는 Restful API Service)</li><li>DB는 DynamoDB 이용<br>이유는 지금 스케일에서 프리티어로 충분해서</li><li>Markdown 문서는 S3에 보관</li></ul><p>데이터 측면에서 관리할 카테고리는</p><ul><li>회원</li><li>글</li><li>게시판</li></ul><p>이다. 글과 게시판 관계는 Medium처럼 한 글이 여러 게시판에 게시될 수 있는 구조이다(N:M).</p><p>기능 측면에서 구현하고자 하는 MVP는</p><ul><li>회원 가입 (Auth)</li><li>글, 게시판 CRUD</li><li>회원 권한 관리</li><li>Markdown Editor 붙이기</li><li>Resource (Image, PDF, etc) S3에 올리고 글에 첨부하기</li></ul><p>정도 생각이 난다.</p><p>프로토타입을 먼저 개발하는 식으로 갈 예정이지만, 자동화나 테스트 부분은 우선적으로 적용 가능하도록 하려고 한다. 아무리 프로토타입이라고 하더라도 귀찮은건 귀찮으니까 말이다. “자동화, 테스트 만드는게 더 귀찮아&quot;라고 말할 수도 있지만 이번엔 나는 자동화, 그리고 TDD를 우선적으로 적용할끼다.</p><p>서버쪽을 먼저 만들어보겠다. ㅂ2.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f4830bc1aac8" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameDevStory 4. Various Attack Type]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-4-various-attack-type-16fc80c9fd2c?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/16fc80c9fd2c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[unreal-engine-4]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[indie-game]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:41:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2016-12-06T21:41:04.627Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello Medium! :D</p><p>I just finished developing all 4 elements. Each element has different attack and skill method. Today I’ll talk about how I implement many different types efficiently.</p><h3>Default Class (Common class)</h3><p>Even if each element has different attack method, there’re many similar things between that methods. For example, dealing damages, shooting bullets or waiting delay. Each element character could have different maximum HP. But It’s the same that they have HP.</p><p>So I created 3 common class; Character, Skill and Bullet. I implement common functions and properties in both class. In later, I would create derived element class or element’s bullet class from Character, Skill or Bullet class.</p><p>In Character class, it handle movement input and getting damage. so it has some properties to handle that, like HP, MaxHP or TeamID.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/886/1*to1jOyae8pJqc4cAWPR5fQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>Character Class’ common functions.</figcaption></figure><h3>Overriding Default Class</h3><p>Definitely new element character might be immortal or couldn’t move. In that case, that functions could be overridden. Let’s check out this case with bullets.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/483/1*Vr0mYmfj6kOt_GFM81OXrA.jpeg" /><figcaption>Bullet is destroyed when they hit something as default.</figcaption></figure><p>I made bullet destroyed when they hit anything. Because I thought many bullets what I would make will be destroyed in that case. So I’d like to set that case as default.</p><p>But wind element’s skill need to keep alive even if it hit anything. So I overrode hit event of wind element’s.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/567/1*zun3bfWIl3vWkCfKC3zhFQ.png" /><figcaption>bullets of wind element’s skill wouldn’t be destroyed even if they hit anything.</figcaption></figure><h3>Introduction of 4 Elements</h3><p>I finally created 4 elements; Fire, Wind, Water and Earth. Each class is the same role with Magician, Archer, Healer and Tanker.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/638/1*kOGBtdYVNW6zO5IMoqvpPA.gif" /><figcaption>Fire Element’s Explosion Skill</figcaption></figure><p>Fire element has high damage per one bullet but casting delay is long. It has explosion skill which could make high damage in short time. I want to make Fire element as Nuker who can deal highest damage in short time.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/638/1*yqNRblSWaMu9qlQPhnBRcA.gif" /><figcaption>Wind Element’s Attack and Skill. … Yes I know effects sucks. But it is prototype yet :D</figcaption></figure><p>Wind element has long range attack with low damage, but fast speed. It also has whirlwind skill. when a whirlwind is summoned, it move slow first but become faster. It make damage all crossed enemy. Yes, it is the same with Janna’s W skill in LOL. I want to make Wind element as damage supporter. Because whirlwind has slow speed first, I thought many users can avoid that. So I felt it’s enough to support dealing damage at back, long distance.</p><p>Water! The Cleric Class! Water element’s default attack is heal for allies, or damage to enemies. It has range between short or medium. The reason is to make killing Water element easy. It’s not fun that only healers remain in battle field at final. Because they have low attack damage. Also, It could be boring If killing healer is very hard because It cause battle time too much longer.</p><p>So, to set healer’s position like below, I set their attack range short.</p><p><strong>Enemies)….. Tanker &lt;— &gt;Water &lt;—&gt; Fire &lt;—&gt; Wind</strong></p><p>The final element is Earth and it is Tanker class. Earth has melee attack and dash skill.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/638/1*Dev8_D7yHKYVDD8vBsjdrg.gif" /><figcaption>Earth’s Melee Attack and Dash Skill.</figcaption></figure><p>When I record above Earth’s skill demo, I just found something. In my previous game project(which is base of this project), I couldn’t make dash skill’s movement smooth. It was dull feeling. Against that, In this time I could make dash skill smooth.</p><p>I felt it’s not better then previous. Because there are no tensions with smooth movement. It just like Heroes of the Storm. I don’t like that feeling. I think I should change this more dull adding breaks.</p><h3>Next Step</h3><p>There is common skill for every elements. That is “Blink” skill. The next step is making Blink skill and set map up to play online demo.</p><p><em>I’m looking for a job in Canada. Please check my </em><a href="https://kr.linkedin.com/in/sehyun-nam-85838774"><em>Linked profile </em></a><em>and contact me (skatpgusskat@naver.com).</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=16fc80c9fd2c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-4-various-attack-type-16fc80c9fd2c">GameDevStory 4. Various Attack Type</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory">GameDevStory</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameDevStory 3. Don’t Send UObject as Data Container via RPC!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-3-dont-send-uobject-as-data-container-via-rpc-15fb674b1597?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/15fb674b1597</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 10:10:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2016-12-02T10:27:41.193Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In general case of C++, to send data through network we serialize a struct. And that struct could be also the class type. (Actually we can assume the struct is almost the same with class)</p><p>So, I need to send skill parameter to server when a player press the skill button. Each skill could have different type of parameters. For example, general shooting skill has starting position and moving direction. A healing skill has reference of target player.</p><p>Do I have to implement skill handler for each skills? I thought I can use function overloading in Unreal Engine 4&#39;s Blueprint. But blueprint dosen’t support function overloading.</p><p>I’d like to solve this problem with the polymorphism, passing parent class instance and handling that in derived class by downcasting.</p><p>For example, I make classes like below,</p><p>SkillParameter (Parent Class)</p><ul><li>SkillParameter_FireExplosion (Derived)</li><li>SkillParameter_Heal (Derived)</li></ul><p>And I pass SkillParameter_Heal upcasting to SkillParameter. Then skill handler process common functions. When I need to customize some function(for example, skill activating function should be re-implement in derived class) I can downcast SkillParameter to specific class. In this case I should downcast SkillParameter to SkillParameter_Heal. Then In skill activating function, I finally could set up healing process.</p><p>That’s what I want to do. So I made SkillParameter deriving UObject. UObject is the only basic class that I can create with in Blueprint. In client side I create SkillParameter instance when the skill button is pressed and I pass that to server by Unreal Engine’s RPC.</p><p>But, unfortunately I faced the problem. In server side, the value of passed SkillParameter was invalid. Yes, it was just a kind of Null.</p><p>There are not enough information with googling. For several hous after I got some clues.</p><p>My guess is that the only UObject reference are passed in RPC. I mean, it isn’t serialized. It just pass reference or something common key of UObject. In common case clients don’t create UObjects itselves. Clients just occur events or call RPC then the server actually create that UObject and replicate it to clients.</p><p>So, definitely the value of SkillParameter passed by client must be invalide because server has no instance of that, Even if client try to pass that reference!</p><p>Finally I changed that design from UObject to UStruct. UStruct is passed with serializing. But I don’t like this solution. Unlike C++’s struct, UStruct dosen’t support inheritance. That mean I can’t use polymorphism and I should choose between 2 options,</p><ol><li>Put every parameter types of every skills into SkillPrameter</li><li>Implement every difference names initializer in child Skill Handler classes and call parent common initializer in child’s.(because UE4&#39;s Blueprint dosen’t support overloading!)</li></ol><p>I think second option is worst. There are no helper that can reject calling wrong function on compile time in blueprint. That mean when child’s custom initializer must be called, parent common initializer could be called by developer’s mistake. I don’t like to give any chance of mistake to developer.</p><p>Even if the first option could make network packet bigger, I thought It is better than second. At now the bandwidth is not problem. So I chose first option. And later I will make inheritable and serializable struct.</p><p>There are no any pictures on today’s post because I wrote this post on my cell phone.</p><p>Anyway, I finished implementing fire element’s skill, attack and move yesterday. My next step is implementing other elements: wind, water, earth in sequence.</p><p>Thanks for read this post. I hope it could be helpful to somebody who try to send Data wrapping with UObject via RPC.</p><p><em>I’m looking for a job in Canada. Please check </em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sehyun-nam-85838774"><em>my Linked profile</em></a><em> and contact me (skatpgusskat@naver.com).</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=15fb674b1597" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-3-dont-send-uobject-as-data-container-via-rpc-15fb674b1597">GameDevStory 3. Don’t Send UObject as Data Container via RPC!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory">GameDevStory</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameDevStory 2. Heroes Never Die!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-2-heroes-never-die-9eb9349bc988?source=rss-561cc4c1cd1------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9eb9349bc988</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[unreal-engine]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[videogames]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ue4]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[indie-game]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Sehyeon  Nam]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:53:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2016-11-29T00:53:50.298Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I developed damage and respawn system. the quote, “Heroes Never Die”, just flashed on me while I think ‘respawn’.</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fgiphy.com%2Fembed%2Fl3vRnKVByM7ewpoe4%2Ftwitter%2Fiframe&amp;src_secure=1&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fgiphy.com%2Fgifs%2Fl3vRnKVByM7ewpoe4&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.giphy.com%2Fmedia%2Fl3vRnKVByM7ewpoe4%2Fgiphy.gif&amp;key=d04bfffea46d4aeda930ec88cc64b87c&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=giphy" width="435" height="244" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/2fff8fff02196fc783d7b1d939ebce5e/href">https://medium.com/media/2fff8fff02196fc783d7b1d939ebce5e/href</a></iframe><h3>Work process</h3><p>Before I started my task, I made work process. Here it is.</p><ul><li>Add HP property in character</li><li>Handle bullet collision reducing HP</li><li>Respawn character when they lost all HP</li></ul><p>Why did I? Because there are many benefits making work process.</p><p>First, I can foresee what should I do. It could sound unnecessary but I think it is very important. Sometimes we waste the time taking a job which is needed to undo. Work is direction. Without any direction on working, we could get lost on forest of tasks.</p><p>Second, I can make a goal and finally I can feel a sense of accomplishment when I finish that. Without a goal, there are only continuous things to do in front of me even if I finished any tasks. Not fun, only stressful situation. So, It could be better making a goal and feel a sense of accomplishment. It’s kind of gamification. Gamification means making something like a game. Sense of accomplishment is one of the important elements of the games. Let’s think that work is game. How wonderful is it? Making a game is the same with making a fun, so it also should be good to feel fun during developing games.</p><p>So, Let’s go to check out how I did.</p><h3>1. Add HP property in character</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/289/1*JNuyQZmkDeghIJDB4TpCSg.png" /></figure><p>I simply added HP property in character class. So simple.</p><h3>2. Handle bullet collision reducing HP</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NNnjvCYy3P6sc-ZUv9xy1A.png" /></figure><p>There is ‘Hit’ event handler in bullet already. I checked the object that collide with bullet has ‘character’ tag. In true condition I dispatched ‘OnDamaged’ event on character, and destroyed that bullet.</p><h3>3. Respawn character when they lost all HP</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*fNdi4P1XVLj4oJ2FCrHJQg.png" /><figcaption>Subtract damage from HP</figcaption></figure><p>When character is damaged, I easily discount the HP. When the HP become equal or lower than 0, I destroy character and notify that to player controller.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6cGGz0NKCOX4fh8n9lbsfw.png" /><figcaption>Call ‘On Character Destoryed’ to Player Controller before destory character.</figcaption></figure><p>I control the character in the character class, not in the player controller, so there are nothing special things to do when the ‘On Character Destroyed’ event is dispatched in player controller. I again pass that event to Game Mode.</p><p>The reason why I just pass it to Game Mode is to separate responsibility. In UE4, Game Mode has the responsibility of <a href="https://docs.unrealengine.com/latest/INT/Gameplay/Framework/GameMode/index.html">below criteria</a>;</p><ul><li>The number of players and spectators present, as well as the maximum number of players and spectators allowed.</li><li>How players enter the game, which can include rules for selecting spawn locations and other <strong><em>spawn/respawn behavior</em></strong>.</li><li>Whether or not the game can be paused, and how pausing the game is handled.</li><li>Transitions between levels, including whether or not the game should start in cinematic mode.</li></ul><p>I spawn new character in Game Mode, and let player controller possess that character.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*sfe2EDptEWj6b0TzqmHM6A.png" /><figcaption>Respawning character on Game Mode</figcaption></figure><p>The important thing is making that logic run on server only, because the server is the only one who we can believe. who knows that some clients hack the system?</p><p>Unfortunately I have no idea what the next step is. I might have to set up the task list with milestones. Yes, I didn’t because this project, at now, is just making previous game project once again in UE4. Hmm… Anyway I need task lists and milestones..!</p><p><em>I’m looking for a job in Canada. Please check my </em><a href="https://kr.linkedin.com/in/sehyun-nam-85838774"><em>Linked profile </em></a><em>and contact me (skatpgusskat@naver.com).</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9eb9349bc988" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory/gamedevstory-2-heroes-never-die-9eb9349bc988">GameDevStory 2. Heroes Never Die!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/gamedevstory">GameDevStory</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>