<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Stories by Kwon Jinhwan on Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Stories by Kwon Jinhwan on Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/fit/c/150/150/0*FxAEzUxpwB0vdl5x.</url>
            <title>Stories by Kwon Jinhwan on Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 10:12:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/@jinkwon711" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EOS wiki page to pdf]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/eos-wiki-page-to-pdf-34e7f2b20627?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/34e7f2b20627</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[eos-wiki]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[github-to-pdf]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[github]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[github-wiki]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[eos]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 01:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-05-02T01:30:41.789Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi guys. I am currently studying EOS these days.</p><p>I always thought that if I could bring github wiki with me wherever I go, it would be nice.</p><p>So I searched and found a Github repository</p><p><a href="https://github.com/yakivmospan/github-wikito-converter">yakivmospan/github-wikito-converter</a></p><p>Yakivmospan made us great tool that we can easily make pdf with Github wiki</p><p>So I tried with eos wiki.</p><p>However it did not work. Because github-wikito-converter does not support EOS Github wiki’s TOC(table of contents , which is _Sidebar.md)</p><p>Also there are some code that github-wikito-converter can not interpret such as yaml and base code in markdown.</p><p>So I recreated TOC and removed yaml and base code format in Markdown</p><p><a href="https://github.com/jinkwon711/eoswiki_pdf">jinkwon711/eoswiki_pdf</a></p><p>here is the wiki for EOS which could be easily transferred to PDF format.</p><p>every steps that you have to follow are instructed in yakivmospan’s github</p><p><a href="https://github.com/yakivmospan/github-wikito-converter">yakivmospan/github-wikito-converter</a></p><p>ps. just let you know <strong>if you are using mac</strong>(with retina display) you should <strong>download 0.12.3 version of wkhtmltopdf</strong> because of the resolution issue(dpi)</p><p><a href="https://github.com/wkhtmltopdf/wkhtmltopdf/releases">wkhtmltopdf/wkhtmltopdf</a></p><p>after download all the appropriate components.</p><p>all you have to do is just type this</p><pre>$ gwtc -f pdf -t eos_wiki ./<a href="https://github.com/jinkwon711/eoswiki_pdf">eoswiki_pd</a>f(path to modified eos wiki repository)</pre><p>You’ll see eos_wiki.pdf at the same directory where you typed a command above.</p><p>All Done!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=34e7f2b20627" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cheap Cryptocurrency at Coinexchange Day-1 Elite]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/cheap-cryptocurrency-at-coinexchange-day-1-elite-c2136c676100?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/c2136c676100</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 13:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-04-26T13:49:12.036Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elite’s price is only 1 satoshi, it is cheapest coin in BTC market now.</p><p>It’s 24 hour transaction amount in BTC volume is 0.87</p><p>It’s total amount of value is 278 BTC</p><p>RANK at 743</p><p><a href="https://www.elitecurrency.net/"><em>https://www.elitecurrency.net</em></a><em> is ELITE’s website</em></p><p>they have 5 team members , which is not good</p><p><a href="https://github.com/xenonflux/1337">github</a> , they only have master branch, only 130 commits, 5 contributors</p><p>no issue tracking in this repository</p><p>→ I am not going to buy this coin haha</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=c2136c676100" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[unfortunately, this project is a private one. Hope you already made it to the end. Thanks]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/unfortunately-this-project-is-a-private-one-hope-you-already-made-it-to-the-end-thanks-b0264cd3c6d4?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b0264cd3c6d4</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 07:57:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-10-27T07:57:49.348Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>unfortunately, this project is a private one. Hope you already made it to the end. Thanks</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b0264cd3c6d4" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2011 to 2017]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/2011-to-2017-6b4bd1f9a316?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6b4bd1f9a316</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 14:52:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-08-28T14:52:06.475Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>대학생이 된지 어느덧 6년 그리고 반년이라는 시간이 지나갔다. 물론 그중 2년은 군대에 있었지만, 적지않은 시간을 보낸 공간을 떠나보낼 시간이 당장 내일로 다가왔다는건 참 신기한 일인 것 같다.</p><p>2011년 난사회과학대학에 입학하여 경제 비반에 배정받았고, 초중고를 같이 나왔지만 오티 끝나고 가는길 모르니까 같이가자는 나의 말을 까먹은 김만수(아직도 기억한다….ㅋㅋ)와 같은반이 되었고, 그리고 40명이 조금 안되는 친구들과(정확한 숫자를 기억못한다..) 재미있는 1년을 보냈다.</p><p>2011년 1학기에는 수업을 2일만 나왔다. 12학점을 들었는데 월 수에 4개를 들어서 깔끔한 주 2를 만들어 내었다. 화요일은 그냥 친구들이랑 놀려고 나왔다. 내 대학생활에서 가장 후회되는 시간이기도하다. 남은 4일을 집에서 와우를 했던 것 같다. 이때 은혜랑 태영이랑 수업을 많이 같이 들었는데. 결국 그 친구들이랑 대학생활동안 연락을 꽤 많이 했던 것 같다. 아직까지도 만나는 몇안되는 친구들이다.</p><p>2011년 여름계절은 탁구랑 배드민턴을 듣고, 세종입을 들었던 것 같다. 세종입들을때 김태영이 열심히 쓴 필기를 잘 썼던 기억도 있는것 같다. 학교에 수업들으러 나오기보단, 체육하면서 놀려고 나왔던터라 매일 트레이닝복을 입고왔었다.</p><p>2011년 가을학기에는 뭘했는지 기억이 잘 안난다. 왜일까...? 하나 기억나는건 지리학입문을 들었는데 그때 재현이랑 말해 볼 기회가 좀 있었다는것? 재현이가 누군지 기억못하는 친구들이 많을 것 같긴 하다. (심리학 입문은 지옥이었다는것도…)</p><p>2011년 겨울계절에는 내 길고긴 경제원론2와의 인연이 시작된 때다 (이때 김태영이 롤을 시작해서 롤 아이디가 경제원론2다). 나는 수업을 드랍했고, 그다음 계절에도 드랍하고, 결국에는 거시경제학을 수강하는 2학년2학기에 경제원론을 듣고 거시보다 성적이 안나왔다.. 후배님들 계절이 꿀입니다..</p><p>2011~2년 겨울은 험난했던것 같다. 아픈 아킬레스건을 부여잡고 12학번들이 기억할지는 모르지만, 누리, 선아, 태영, 그리고 미영이와 함께 비스트의 숨(Breath, 이제는 하이라이트가 되어버린 비스트..)를 이제는 대모님이 되신 원더걸스의 Be My Baby를 열심히 췄다. 새삼 생각해보니 앞으로 이름날리실 분들과 함께 춤을! 당시 이건주랑 백유경이 나랑 김태영얼굴에 장난을 쳤는데, 그사진은 어디갔는진 모르겠다. 아 그리고 이때 아킬레스건 아프기전에 스키장 갔었는데 근우, 민구, 선아, 태영 , 미영?!, 동생이 아버지랑 싸워서 스키장안와서 아주 큰방 2개에 6명이 써서 모두다 각방을 쓰는기적이 일어났지. 그리고 어떠한 사건(?) 때문에 내 스키를 도둑맞아서 물어줬던 기억도..(그때 다들 돈 모아서 같이부담해줘서 감동받았어…)</p><p>2012년 봄학기, 새로운 친구들이 들어왔다. 생각해보면 별로 해준게 없었던것 같기도. 이제는 다 커버린 후배들이 되어버렸다. 나보다 더 어른인듯 ㄷㄷ , 내 대학생활 내내 가장 기억이 없던 2012년 왜냐하면 군대가서 다까먹어서..? 그리고.. 남우현과 녹두 달콤에서 자주 이야기를 나누었던것 같다.(2학기일지도 모른다) 남우현보고있나.</p><p>2012년 여름, 비반 친구들이랑 이때 캠프를 갔는데. 내 군생활 할때 이쪽으로 행군을 가서 기분이 매우 착잡…. 그 때 캠프에서 공포체험했는데 조은영이 운것같았는데..말이지.</p><p>2012년 가을학기에는 전공을 본격적으로 들었던것 같다. 거시들을때 태현이의 도움이 참 컸다.</p><p>2012~13년 겨울에는 또 스키장 갔던것 같고, 이제 슬슬 남자로 태어난 이래 …최고로 거지같은 시간을 지낼 준비를 할때였다.</p><p>2013~2014년은 인생의 암울한 시간이었다… 군대… 짧게 언급해보자면, 나는 육군이었는데, 선임들이 사고치고, 후임들은 간부랑 싸우고, 동기는 맹장염 걸리고 해서 여러명 일을 한꺼번에 했는데 정말 죽는줄 알았다. 대신 휴가는 그만큼 많이 나와서, 좋긴했지만, 개인 정비시간이 너무나 없었던 군 생활. , 그리고 일병 때 즈음인가. 우울함과 함께 불면증이 찾아왔는데. 이때 그냥 병원을 갈 껄 그랬다. 별 문제없다고 생각하고 지냈는데, 하루하루가 피폐해 지더라. 잠이 안와서 12시까지 공부하는 곳에서..친구들과 수다떨고.. 12시에 들어가서 누우면 한 2시즘 잠이 올까 말까였는데, 한 3시즈음에 불침번이라고 깨우는 순간, 그날 잠은 다 잤다.. 아무튼, 바쁜 군 생활에 계획한 영어 공부도 못해서 교환학생 가는걸 한 학기 미뤄야했다.</p><p>2015년 1학기는 원래대로라면 교환 학생을 가고 싶었던 학기었지만, 지난 학기에 토플점수를 따지 못하여(빌어먹을군대..) 남은 전공과목을 듣기로 하였다. 제대하면 복학생 버프가 있다는 소리를 듣고, 패기있게 전공들과 선형대수를 신청하고, 이때 강민구랑 나는 피똥을 쌌다. 복학버프는 무슨. 공부를 하면할수록 성적이 떨어지는 기이한현상을 경험했다지.</p><p>2015년 2학기는 내 인생에 참 많은것이 바뀐 해였다. 독일 교환학생을 가게 되었는데, 사실은 영어권을 쓰고 싶었으나, 갑작스레 영국에서 토플을 안받고 아이엘츠만 받겠다고 하여, 많은 학생들이 영국을 쓰지못하게 되어, 영어를 쓰는지역의 교환학생 경쟁률이 크게 올라가서, 그냥 독일을 쓰게 되었다. 나는 독일 아헨이라는 도시에서 교환학생 생활을 하게되었는데, 아헨공과대학(RWTH)는 교환학생 비율이 매우매우 높은 학교라고한다. 공대임에도 불구하고 베를린, 뮌헨, 아헨 공과대학은 경제&amp;경영학부가 있는데 나는 경제학부에서 경제 및 경영수업을 들었다. 당시 교수님이 한국분이어서 좀 신기했다. 그 한국 교수님이 하시는 수업이 Applied Economic Modeling이었는데, GAMS라는 프로그램을 이용하여, 균형상태에 외부충격이 가해지면, 새로운 균형이 어떻게 될것인가를 모델링해보는 수업이었다. 이 수업을 들으면서 , 한가지 깨달은건, 경제학적 모델링 지식이 아니라, 내 자신이 컴퓨터를 가지고 무엇을 하는걸 더 좋아한다는 것이었다. 이 뿐만 아니라 , 처음으로 유럽여행을 하게 되었고, 이 당시에 여행하면서 만난 사람들과 아직까지도 연락을 하고 지낸다. Yang Xin, Ivan Koo, Zihan Meng, 청 누나, 준영이형, 현균이, 채영이형, 지안이, 수영누나, 아해 그리고 많은 친구들..</p><p>2016년 봄학기에는 컴퓨터 공학 부전공을 신청하였다. 당시에 바로듣지는 못하였기에, 다음학기에 수월하게 듣기위해, 경제와 경영부전공을 마무리하려고 빡시게 들었다. 되게 바보같지만.. 경영부전공으로는 인정이안되는 인사관리를 포함하여 21학점을 들어버려서 나중에 계절에 생산관리를 또 듣게 되었다. 초급독일어도 수강하였는데, 사실 독일에서 반년 살았지만, 이때 처음으로 독일어를 공부하게 되었다 ㅋㅋ</p><p>2016년 여름학기에는 본격적으로 프로그래밍에 입문하였다. Python과 Django를 이용하여 웹페이지를 제작해보는 비전공자를 위한 동아리 P-rogramming에 들어갔다. 이 동아리 3기 회장이 우리반 박근우라는 재미있는 사실… 이때부터 프로그래밍에 맛들려 열심히 살았던것같다. 컴퓨터로 게임하는시간이 당연히 길었던 17년간의 생활을 청산하고, 컴퓨터로 공부를 더 오래하게되었다.</p><p>2016년 가을학기는 말그대로 지옥이었다. 4학년 2학기에 시작한 컴퓨터공학 부전공때문에 17학점을 모두 전공으로 채워서 들었는데 , 2학년과목인 컴퓨터프로그래밍 과목에서 엄청난 양의 과제가 나왔다. 그당시 그 수업을 들었던 친구들은 아마 날 알거다. 좌측앞에서 항상 교수님이 피드백달라고하면 손들고 나는 이렇게 말했다. “교수님 과제가 너무 많아요”. 이 당시에 친구 한명은 이런 명언을 남겼다. “조교님의 감성을 이해할수 없어요” 많은 학생들이 공감하며 크게 웃었었다.</p><p>2016~2017년 겨울학기에는 피로그래밍 6기 친구들의 멘토역할을 하며 참가했다. 이번방학도 쉬기는 글렀다. 선홍이라는 친구가 아주 열정이 뛰어났다. 희탁이는 지금 소프트웨어마이스터?를 하고있고, 현규는 장사를, 지영이는 프리랜서, 그리고 지연이는 독일로 교환학생을 갔다.</p><p>2017년 1학기에는 딱 두가지를 들었다. 종합격투기를 가르쳐주는 체력단련 수업과, 컴퓨터 부전공의 마지막 과목 시스템프로그래밍. 아무래도 마지막이다보니까 학교를 좀 설렁설렁다녔나보다. 성적은 뭐 설렁설렁 다닌만큼 나왔다. 하이닉스 면접도 보러가서 털리고, CJ랑 아모레도 썼는데 서류에서 다떨구더라.. 퉷.. 어쨋든 학기가 마무리가 되었다. 이후 여름방학 기간(이미끝난마당에 방학이란 없지만..)에 여러가지 복잡한 일도 있었다. 친구와 함께 일본여행도 다녀왔다. 하는 것 없이 친구랑 먹으러 돌아다니기만 했다. 심지어 전날의 숙취때문에 아침을 제대로 못먹은 날은 저녁을 두번먹기위해 5시에 먹고 한 세네시간 열심히 걸어다니고 8시경에 또 먹었다. 토리텐과 텐동은 잊지 못할듯! 아무튼 오랫동안 기억 될 좋은 여행이었다.</p><p>그리고 저번에 사진을 올려서 많은 분들이 아시겠지만, 지금은 네이버에서 개발자로 일을 하고있다.</p><p>그리고 지금 난 내일 졸업식을 앞두고 있다.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6b4bd1f9a316" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thanks.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/thanks-775b718f8ddd?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/775b718f8ddd</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 03:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-08-28T03:00:42.202Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thanks.</p><p>When I have little more time,</p><p>I am sure gonna do that. but currently I got a job so I’m little busy~!</p><p>I’ll try to update google login when I use google login feature.</p><p>Thanks again for the lovely comment.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=775b718f8ddd" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hi there~!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/hi-there-7a901a32b4b1?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/7a901a32b4b1</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 02:58:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-08-28T02:58:16.398Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi there~!</p><p>It has been quite a long time since I posted it.</p><p>So I am not sure, but try this.</p><p>SITE ID is prime key number for you site object. if you go to django’s admin’s site section. you’ll see your site setting object’s primekey(pk/Id)</p><p>probably 1 or 2 .. or maybe if you made object and deleted several times, Site Id will be grater than 1 or 2</p><p>Anyway</p><p>In conclusion try “SITE_ID=1”</p><p>if not working go to admin’s site section and find the id of the site object</p><p>hope you succeed with it! bye!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=7a901a32b4b1" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hi , thanks for the good explanation on reinforcement learning.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/hi-thanks-for-the-good-explanation-on-reinforcement-learning-18b28f2c0f1c?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/18b28f2c0f1c</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 01:53:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-08-22T01:53:23.048Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi , thanks for the good explanation on reinforcement learning.</p><p>Do you mind if I translate your posts in Korean?</p><p>As your posts are really helpful, I thought that this could be also useful for others who cannot read English well.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=18b28f2c0f1c" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scala setting on Intellij from install to build]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/scala-setting-on-intellij-from-install-to-build-d30eba7f30ab?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d30eba7f30ab</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[intellij]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[intellij-idea]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[scala]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 07:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-07-27T07:27:56.999Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are many ways to build program, you can choose to build codes with maven which are quite famous and easy. If you are using IntelliJ (Comnunity version is good enought), you can build your program more easily</p><p>first you have to download intellij</p><p><a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/download/">Download IntelliJ IDEA: The Java IDE for Professional Developers by JetBrains</a></p><p>If you use community edition, as it is an open source, it is free.</p><p>anyway after install the IntelliJ , you also have to download the scala plugin.</p><p>Go to<strong> IntelliJ IDEA/Preference(in Mac)</strong> which is in left top of the corner.</p><p>There, you can find <strong>“Plugins” </strong>, obviously click it.</p><p>Then also you can see “ Browse Repositories, also click it. then another pop-up window will be popped. there you can search <strong>“scala”</strong> → you should download language.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*I158asRmv4A3UIX9Xn4pvA.png" /><figcaption>download this plugin! “SCALA”!!!!!</figcaption></figure><p>Now you can write your code easily.</p><p>Other options such as configuring folder hierachy, naming, blabla … are quite same as Java</p><p>So, if you want to create new class, object, or trait of scala , then do right click a folder.</p><p>Before you make scala source code file, you have to modify a folder as Source Root. Then you can generate scala class or object files.</p><p>Now, I think you are pretty much done making initial setup.</p><p>While you write your own code, you probably have to use third party pacakages or anything that is not in scala package.</p><p>Configuring dependency is quite easy compared to configuring in terminal via commandline.</p><p>Go to <strong>File/Project Structure</strong>. Go to <strong>Libraries</strong> , click <strong>+</strong> to add dependencies.</p><p>choose “<strong>from maven</strong>” then you will have a pop-up windows where you can search library files.</p><p>After you find what you want, click OK, click project folder which you want to use that library, press OK</p><p>Do as much as you want.</p><p>After you finish with your codes , you probably going to make executable file (.jar)</p><p>There are few steps in order to build a jar file.</p><p>First we need to select which module(with dependency) you are going to build with .</p><p>Go to <strong>File/Project Structure</strong> , go to <strong>Artifacts, </strong>click <strong>+</strong> .</p><p>Click Jar, module with dependencies…</p><p>choose the module that you configured with dependencies</p><p>choose your main class to execute, and click OK</p><p>After you have finished configuring artifacts settings.</p><p>On the top menu bar, you can find <strong>Build/Build Artifacts -&gt; build</strong></p><p>Your .jar file will be located at “out/artifacts/&lt;module name&gt;</p><p>We are done! Congrat.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d30eba7f30ab" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Well.. honestly I have no idea about the problem.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/well-honestly-i-have-no-idea-about-the-problem-60cc83b77c3e?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/60cc83b77c3e</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 05:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-05-01T05:36:57.489Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well.. honestly I have no idea about the problem. In korea where I live, there are many web pages with facebook login, and when I log in with facebook login module , it also makes facebook to be logged in.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=60cc83b77c3e" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[프로그래머가 유튜브 다운받는법]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/@jinkwon711/%ED%94%84%EB%A1%9C%EA%B7%B8%EB%9E%98%EB%A8%B8%EA%B0%80-%EC%9C%A0%ED%8A%9C%EB%B8%8C-%EB%8B%A4%EC%9A%B4%EB%B0%9B%EB%8A%94%EB%B2%95-8e77e35fafc2?source=rss-7c2b231928f0------2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/8e77e35fafc2</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[shell-script]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[python]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[youtube-dl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Kwon Jinhwan]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 09:50:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2017-03-04T09:50:12.470Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<pre>l<strong>Youtube-dl 과 shell script 로 유튜브 동영상 자동으로 다운받는 스크립트 만들기</strong></pre><p>youtube의 영상을 다운받는 방법은 매우 여러가지가 있습니다.</p><p>하지만 프로그래머, 소프트웨어엔지니어, 뭐라고 부르던, 코딩을 하는사람들은 youtube-dl 을 많이 씁니다.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl">youtube-dl 깃허브 주소</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl">https://github.com/rg3/youtube-dl</a></p><p>뭘누르던 들어가집니다.</p><p>자세한 사용법은 영어로 쓰여있기 때문에 과감히 스킵 합니다.</p><blockquote><em>영알못이라…. 인간적으로 옵션이 너무 많습니다.</em></blockquote><p>그래서 우리는 딱 하나 youtube-dl의 기본옵션인 youtube-dl 명령어를 option없이 씁니다.</p><p>먼저 맥북 기준으로 터미널을 열어서</p><p>pip3 install youtube-dl</p><p>을 해줍니다.</p><p>사실 리눅스도 똑같습니다. pip3 가 안깔려있는 노트북의 경우는 pip3 를 깔아줍니다.</p><p>pip3 는 파이썬 3 를 설치한뒤 깔면 됩니다. 가장 편한건 아나콘다 파이썬을 깔면 한방에 해결이 되죠 <a href="https://www.continuum.io/downloads">https://www.continuum.io/downloads</a> 여기서 다운받으시면됩니다.</p><p>자 youtube-dl이 제대로 깔렸나 확인하기위해 커맨드라인에서</p><p>youtube-dl &lt;youtube-url&gt;</p><p>을 쳐줍니다.</p><p>물론 &lt;youtube-url&gt;은 실제 동영상의 url을 넣어주면 됩니다.</p><p>&lt;&gt;이거 넣지마세요 ㅠㅠ</p><p>자 다운이 잘 됩니까?</p><blockquote>안되면 ……</blockquote><blockquote>스스로 해결해보는 능력을 기르는 좋은 기회가…….</blockquote><p>그럼이제 shell script 를 배워봅시다.</p><pre>​<br>#!/bin/bash<br>​<br>echo &quot;youtube downloader&quot;<br>echo &quot;paste folder name which will store videos&quot;<br>read folder_name<br>echo &quot;make sure your urls.txt file and this sh codes are at the same directory &quot;<br>mkdir ./$folder_name<br>echo $(pwd) &quot;this is your current directory&quot;<br>echo &quot;files will be downloaded at $(pwd)/$folder_name&quot;<br>echo &quot;default option is &#39;youtube-dl&#39;&quot;<br>echo &quot;if you want to download in higher resolution&quot; <br>echo &quot;plz change the shell script&quot;<br>lines=&quot;../urls.txt&quot;<br>cd $folder_name<br>​<br>while read line<br>do<br>    youtube-dl --format mp4 $line<br>done&lt;&quot;$lines&quot;</pre><p>간단히 짜본 코드입니다.</p><p>한줄한줄 설명들어갑니다.</p><p>첫줄의</p><p>\#!/bin/bash 는 이 코드가 쉘스크립트라는것을 알려줍니다.</p><p>echo는 사실상 그냥 print랑 같다고 보시면됩니다.</p><p>read는 python 의 input과 같은역할을 합니다.</p><p>변수를 받을때는 $없이, 변수를 사용할떄는 $와 함께 사용합니다.</p><p>read folder_name은 사용자로부터 입력을 받아서 그 문자열을 folder_name에 저장하는것입니다.</p><p>이 folder_name을 사용하고자 할 때는 $folder_name으로 꼭 $$$$$$$$$$이걸 붙여줘야합니다.</p><p>while문법은 조금 생소한 방법인데</p><pre>while read line</pre><pre>do</pre><pre>​ blabla~~</pre><pre>done&lt;&quot;$lines&quot;</pre><p>라고 되어있습니다.</p><p>이는 lines에서 한줄씩 읽어오고 lines가 고갈될때까지 와일문을 돌린다는 이야기 입니다.</p><p>물론 blabla에는 와일문 한번씩 돌 때마다 할 내용을 지정해주면 됩니다.</p><p>위에 보면lines = &quot;../urls.txt&quot;로 urls.txt에 우리가 받고싶은 url주소를 한줄한줄 입력해 놓으면됩니다.</p><p>youtube list로 된 비디오면 리스트가 주소에 포함된 url을 넣으면 한번에 리스트 전체가 받아집니다.</p><p>해당 스크립트는 urls.txt와 같은 디렉토리에 넣어주시면, 스크립트가 입력을 받아서 폴더생성해주고 그 폴더안에 urls.txt안에 들은 주소에 있는 영상을 다운받아줍니다.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=8e77e35fafc2" width="1" height="1">]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>